Benjamin Cato

With over a decade of experience in **front-end development**, I thrive on infusing projects with creativity and passion. I excel in collaborative environments and approach each project as a work of art, taking pride in my role as the artist.

402 Bridgepoint Ln.
Woodstock, GA 30189
(404) 374-1696
bcato3000@gmail.com
bcato3000.github.io/portfolio

EXPERIENCE

Capstone Logistics, Atlanta — *Lead front-end developer*

Jan 2024 - Present

Front-end and limited back-end web development for Vue 3 JS/TS SPA for logistics and dispatching applications \cdot Team lead for our web portal team \cdot Liaison between UX design and developers \cdot Mentor of junior front-end devs

Whereoware, Atlanta — Senior front-end developer

May 2023 - October 2023

Expertise in creating modular components via React and Storybook (via TypeScript)
• Optimizing user interfaces for Optimizely & Sitecore (CMS) • Involved with
front-end code review of PRs • Expertise in responsive web development (mobile
devices and desktop) and pixel-perfect UI • Team lead for multiple front-end
projects • Composition breakdown of components • AA SEO optimization • Mentor of
junior front-end devs • Development for companies such as: Vector and Connectwise

BrainJocks / Perficient, Alpharetta — Lead front-end developer

December 2021 - May 2023

Returned to Brainjocks / Perficient · Created SPAs via React for large-scale CMS platforms (Sitecore 8 & 9 / Optimizely) · Modular components and applications via React and Storybook (via TypeScript) · Responsive web development expertise (mobile devices and desktop) · AA & AAA SEO optimization · HTML5 / CSS3 / Sass / LESS and JS · Design liaison · Mentor of junior front-end devs · Client-facing and development for clients such as: Cooks Children's Hospital, Publix, and Sage

Fleetcor, Atlanta — Senior front-end developer

August 2020 - December 2021

Front-end development fintech · Collaborated with UI / UX designers and bridged the gap between graphical representations and technical implementation via vanilla JS, D3 Js for graphical interface · Creator of global component library for enterprise purposes · Provided front-end expertise for HTML / CSS / JS · Unit-tests via Jest

BrainJocks / Perficient, Alpharetta — Lead front-end developer

April 2013 - July 2020

Created SPAs via React for large-scale CMS platforms (Sitecore, Optimizely) · Modular components and applications via React and Storybook (via TypeScript) · Responsive web development expertise (mobile devices and desktop) · AA SEO optimization · HTML5 / CSS3 / Sass / LESS / JS · Design liaison · UI instructor of SCORE (our customized front-end software) · Mentor of junior front-end devs · Client-facing and development for clients such as: P&G, Honeywell, Central Garden & Pet, Marcus & Millichap, and Pergo

SKILLS (# of years)

HTML5 (10+)

CSS3 (10+)

Sass (10+)

JavaScript (10+)

jQuery (7)

TypeScript (4)

Storybook (4)

RESTful APIs (5)

SPAs (React/Vue) (4)

Node (5)

Web components (1)

Responsive design/dev (10+)

Cross-browser (10+)

Accessibility standards (8)

Git (8)

UX (10)

Adobe creative suite (7)

Sketch App (5)

Figma (4)

Agile / Scrum (10+)

Client-facing contributor (8)

PC Windows (10+)

Mac iOS (10+)

EDUCATION

 $\textbf{The Creative Circus,} \ \textbf{Atlanta} - \textbf{Interactive Development}$

Graduate: 2012 - 2013

Chattahoochee Tech, Acworth — *Computer Science*

Graduate 2001 - 2003

 ${\bf Kennesaw\ State\ University,\ Kennesaw\ -\it Computer\ Science}$

1997 - 2000